Actually, there's one more person who knows her secret.
事實上，還有一個人知道
This person's name is…
那個人的名字就是…
Yun Tae-o.
尹泰晤
Her boyfriend.
就是她的戀人
Tae-o…
泰晤…
knows about my power?
知道我能力的事？
I knew it.
果然沒錯
So, you really are dating someone named Yun Tae-o.
你的男友真的叫尹泰晤啊？
But…
不過…
What does this mean?
這是怎麼回事？
I heard about all of this
告訴我這件事的人
from Professor Iiyama, who teaches at Tae-o's graduate school.
是飯山教授
It seems that Professor Iiyama found out about your power
飯山教授發現你的能力後
and told Tae-o about it.
就跟他全盤托出
But Tae-o already knew about it before I told him.
不過泰晤在我跟他講之前 就已經知情了
At this rate, something bad might happen to the two of them.
再這樣下去 他們倆可能會遇到不好的事情
So, could you please force the two of them to break up?
所以我想拜託你
Is it true?
這是真的嗎？
Does Tae-o really know about my power?
泰晤竟然知道我有那種能力？
It's hard to believe.
不敢相信
If your boyfriend
假如他啊
is trying to hide it,
真的隱瞞了此事
he may have his own reasons for doing so.
或許他有一些苦衷
Are you prepared for what's to come?
你做好覺悟了嗎？
Let's recap.
我們先整理一下現況
Number one. Does Tae-o really know about your power?
“一，泰晤真的知道 侑里小姐能力的事嗎？
Number two. When did he find out?
二，他是從什麼時候知道的？
Number three. Who in the world is Professor Iiyama?
三，飯山教授到底是什麼人？”
There's one thing that really bothers me.
我最在意的是
If Tae-o knows my power,
若他知道我的能力
why is he keeping that a secret from me?
為什麼要隱瞞呢？
That's true.
就是說啊
Why is he keeping it a secret from you?
“為何泰晤要瞞著侑里小姐？”
Let's look into that.
我們來釐清那一點吧
How?
怎麼釐清？
All you can do is ask him directly.
這個嘛，只能直接問本人吧
I can't do that.
我做不到啦
We're not even sure if he really knows or not.
而且我根本不確定 他是不是真的對此知情
Then translation is our only option.
那就只能靠翻譯了
Translation?
翻譯？
You'll translate Tae-o's thoughts into Japanese.
把泰晤的心聲翻成日語
How?
要怎麼做？
We have the perfect time and place for that.
不是正好有個適當的機會嗎？
ANNUAL PERFORMANCE REVIEW WITH CEO
（社長面談時間表）
The performance review?
社長面談？
Today's meeting is with Kame, right?
排在今天的是龜哥啊？
You know, I look forward to this performance review every year.
咱每年都很期待社長面談哪
You do?
是這樣啊？
Aren't you nervous?
不會緊張嗎？
No. Boss takes the time to let me talk about my daughter every year.
不會，每年社長 都會親切地聽咱說女兒的事
-Don't you see, Aihara? -Let's push his meeting to next week.
-相原，你懂嗎？ -龜哥的面談就延到下星期吧
-What? -All right then.
-什麼？ -好
Let's do this, Yuri.
開始行動吧，侑里小姐
U-Um…
嗯…
Can you really keep dating Tae-o and act like you don't know anything?
你有辦法裝作什麼都不知道
You're right.
你說得對
If you want to open the door to his heart, you need to make the first move
如果想打開泰晤的心門
and knock.
去主動敲門才行
Yeah.
好
Come in.
請進
Take a seat.
請坐
Okay.
好
Want to get some coffee?
要去喝杯咖啡嗎？
-Sure. -All right.
-好 -嗯
We'll start this review with a stress check.
這次面談會先進行壓力檢測
A stress check?
壓力檢測？
Yes, a stress check.
對，壓力檢測
It's a part of the review.
這也是面談的一部分
I see.
這樣啊
Now, let's begin.
那我要開始了
Okay.
好的
In a land far, far away, there once lived
在某個地方
a sea otter and a dog who were friends.
有一隻海獺和一隻小狗很要好
A sea otter?
海獺嗎？
The sea otter had a delicious tangerine,
海獺有好吃的橘子
but kept it a secret from the dog.
可是不讓小狗知道此事
The sea otter has a tangerine?
海獺有橘子？
But the dog had actually
不過其實小狗啊
found out about the secret.
早就發現那個祕密了
The sea otter… A tangerine.
海獺有橘子
Now, then.
問題是…
What would you do if you were the dog?
你是小狗的話，會怎麼做？
"You can send it"?
“可以送出去”
Send what?
送什麼？
Sea otters don't eat tangerines.
海獺不吃橘子
That's true, but…
是這樣沒錯啦…
Sea otters like to eat sea urchins or clams.
海獺喜歡的是海膽或蛤蜊
Um…
呃…
That wasn't the point.
那不是重點…
Also, sea otters and dogs live in different habitats.
再加上海獺和小狗棲息地不一樣
Like I said, that wasn't the point.
就跟你說那不是我要問的…
THE GREEN ONIONS WENT INSIDE
（有放蔥吧）
"The green onions went inside"?
“有放蔥吧”？
This isn't working.
這招行不通啊
YURI, LET'S CALL OFF THE PLAN
（侑里小姐，取消計畫）
What?
什麼？
Is something the matter?
那個，你怎麼了？
Not at all.
沒事
That makes the end
壓力檢測到此為止
Is it over?
結束了？
Yes, that's enough.
對，已經夠了
-Boss. -Yes?
-社長 -是
Isn't there anything else you want to ask me?
你沒有其他事情要問我嗎？
What?
什麼？
You can ask me anything.
要問什麼都可以喔
Thank you for today.
今天非常感謝你
I hope you'll consider our proposal.
再麻煩你考慮看看
Yes, I look forward to giving you a positive response.
好的，我會積極考慮
Thank you.
謝謝
Our office is nearby. If you have time, would you like to visit?
敝公司就在附近，如果有空的話 要不要到辦公室看看？
I'd like you to meet our CEO too.
我想向你介紹敝公司的負責人
Yes, I'd love to.
好啊，我很想去
Kame, can you show me this month's sales chart?
龜哥，可以讓我看一下 這個月的銷售報表嗎？
-This one. -Thank you.
-在這裡 -謝謝
We'll move on to Special Plan C.
改成執行特別C計畫
Please continue to look into Tae-o's thoughts.
侑里小姐請繼續探聽泰晤的心聲
I call it Operation Sleepover!
其名為“過夜大作戰”
Don't let me go home tonight.
“今晚別讓我回家啦”
I'll go meet Professor Iiyama.
我會去見飯山教授
Don't worry. I've got just the trick.
別擔心，我正好有個好幫手
Please, right this way.
請進，就是這裡
We have two departments. A lifestyle department and kitchen department.
我們將空間分成生活部門和廚房部門
The lifestyle department mainly develops ideas for daily essentials.
生活部門主要從事日用品的企劃開發
The kitchen department…
而廚房部門…
I wonder…
泰晤…
does Tae-o really know about my power?
真的察覺我有這份能力了嗎？
Ms. Min?
閔小姐？
Let me introduce you.
我來為你介紹
I'm sorry.
不好意思
I actually have to go now.
我就先告辭了
Ms. Min?
閔小姐？
This is my desk.
這裡就是我的座位
It does seem on-brand for you.
很有小野田先生的風格呢
You really do only show interest in your research subjects.
有一種只對研究對象感興趣的感覺
So, where is Professor Iiyama?
想問一下，飯山教授在哪裡呢？
Huh?
什麼？
I was curious.
我想見見他
He hasn't been here since yesterday.
教授從昨天開始就沒來了
He hasn't?
他沒來？
I wonder what happened.
他是怎麼了啊？
Who knows?
不知道耶
Maybe he found a new research subject.
他大概是找到新的研究對象了吧
I'll go home for today then.
那我今天就先回去了
Huh? Wait.
不會吧？等一下…
Huh?
幹嘛？
Do you really want to leave now?
你真的要回去嗎？
For today, yes.
是啊，我今天就先走了
This is my workplace.
這裡是我上班的地方
In other words, it's a chance for you to learn more about me.
換句話說，現在是進一步 了解我的大好機會
Huh?
什麼？
Am I the only one who wants to learn more here?
只有我想更加了解你嗎？
Don't you want to learn more about me, Mahiro?
真尋小姐，你不想多認識我嗎？
MAHIRO IKEMOTO HAS SENT A MESSAGE
（池本真尋傳來訊息）
Professor Iiyama was away.
飯山教授不在
It seems he hasn't come lately.
他最近好像都沒來大學
-Tae-o. -Huh?
-泰晤 -哦？
What is it, Boss?
社長，怎麼了？
Do you want to…
今天…
have a date at my home today?
要不要在我家約會？
An at-home date?
在家約會嗎？
Yeah, an at-home date.
對，沒錯，就是在家約會
Yeah, sounds nice.
當然，好呀
Let's go. It'll be our first at-home date.
走吧，這是我們第一次在家約會呢
Yeah.
是啊
These are Hypselodoris festiva.
這些是節慶多彩海蛞蝓
I see.
原來如此…
The Armina papillata I'm studying are endangered in some regions.
我研究的乳突片鰓海蛞蝓 在某些地區瀕臨絕種
So, by studying a sea slug with similar life patterns--
所以我用生態有點類似的 這些節慶多彩海蛞蝓…
I see.
原來如此
And with that, let's start dating.
那我們交往吧
-What? -To learn about each other,
-什麼？ -要了解對方的話
we start by dating.
首先要交往啊
I told you.
我說過吧？
This is the only way I'll know.
我要先了解才知道能不能交往
But to learn more about a romance between you and me,
可是我和你的戀愛
both you and I have to take part.
必須由我們兩個實際談過 才知道可不可行
Your way of thinking is way too different from my own.
你的思維和我差太多了
It's precisely because we have trouble understanding things
但就是因為無法理解
that we become curious.
才會有興趣啊，對吧？
I see.
這樣啊
That must be why I'm so interested in you.
所以我才會如此在意你
You're interested
你是真的在意…
in me?
我的事？
I am. Incredibly so.
是啊，可以說是非常在意
Then how about you and I start dating?
既然這樣，我們就交往吧
You have a point.
有道理耶
The species that survive are ones that continue to change and adapt.
隨時都能接受和適應變化的物種 才能存活下來
Huh?
什麼東西？
We're on the brink of mass extinction.
也就是說這世界進入了大滅絕時代
Let's survive this time together.
讓我們一起在這個時代存活下來吧
Yes, if you insist.
那就沒辦法了
From here on out, let's survive this together.
從今以後，也一起存活下去吧
For you and your life.
讓我存在於你的人生中
What was that?
你要幹嘛？
Huh?
啥？
What?
什麼？
Hm?
嗯？
I'll cook today.
今天我來做菜
That's great.
我好高興
Oh, right.
對了
Let's take a photo.
來拍照吧
-Yuri. -Yes?
-侑里小姐 -是
Look here.
請看這邊
Kimchi.
泡菜
Kimchi?
泡菜？
Yeah. Kimchi.
對，泡菜
Kimchi.
泡菜
Kimchi!
泡菜！
So cute.
好可愛啊
I haven't cooked in a while.
我很久沒下廚了
Sorry it's taking so long.
所以要花很多時間，對不起
No, it's okay.
沒關係啦
I'll help. Here.
我也會幫忙，就在這邊
Thank you.
謝謝
Wow, looks tasty.
天啊，看起來好好吃
Give it a taste.
你試吃看看
Are you going to tell me to open wide?
難道你要餵我吃嗎？
Open wide? Oh, sure.
餵你吃？哦，好啊
Is it good?
好吃嗎？
Mm.
嗯
It's good.
好吃
What a relief.
太好了
But in my umma's soondubu…
不過“媽媽”的“豆腐鍋”…
we put this in.
會加入這個
Oyster sauce?
蠔油？
-Yeah. -Oh, can you put it in?
-對 -好，那你加進去吧
Okay then.
好
Now, open wide.
來，張嘴
Mm, that's so good!
天啊，超好吃！
So good.
很好吃！
So, this is God's secret ingredient.
這就是神的豆腐鍋的提味祕方啊
Good to know.
學到了一課
All right.
那麼…
Let's eat.
我開動了
I've been wondering for a while, but what does that mean?
我從之前就想問了，那是什麼意思？
Oh, it means, "Enjoy your food."
哦，是“請好好享用”的意思
Masissge meogeoyo.
“masissge meogeoyo”
Such kind words.
好溫柔的一句話
Enjoy your food.
請好好享用
-Let's eat.
-我開動了 -開動了
Enjoy.
快吃吧
Thank you for the food.
我吃飽了
Thank you.
感謝招待
Was it good?
料理好吃嗎？
Of course, uri Yuri made it.
當然好吃，因為是“uri yuri”做的
Uri Yuri?
“uri yuri”？
What does that mean?
那是什麼意思？
Uri Yuri.
“uri yuri”
It means "My Yuri."
意思是“我的侑里小姐”
So, I'm your Uri?
所以我是屬於你的？
Yeah.
對
For the "u" sound,
說“u”的時候
move your mouth more like this.
嘴巴要這樣
Huh?
什麼？
Keep your mouth like that.
嘴唇請維持這個樣子
Please wait a moment.
請等一下
-Five minutes. -Huh?
-五分鐘就好 -什麼？
What is Operation Sleepover?
你說的過夜大作戰是什麼意思？
Listen, Yuri.
仔細聽好，侑里小姐
Nothing can beat when couples are flirting with each other.
情侶互相調情的時光是無敵的
Flirting with each other?
情侶互相調情的時光？
That's the only time you can get away with asking anything.
唯獨在那個時候 不管你問什麼，對方都會原諒
Flirting with each other?
情侶互相調情的時光？
Here.
來
-Huh? -Take it.
-什麼？ -請收下
Uri Yuri.
“uri yuri”
Tae-o, I…
泰晤，我…
Yuri.
侑里小姐
Will you…
我們…
Yuri!
侑里小姐！
Thanks for waiting.
讓你久等了
What is it?
怎麼了？
No, it's nothing.
不，沒什麼
Yuri.
侑里小姐
Let's wear this together.
我們一起穿吧
They're matching sets.
是一樣的款式喔
Huh?
什麼東西？
Couple pajamas.
情侶睡衣
Couple pajamas?
情侶睡衣？
Does it look okay?
會不會很奇怪？
It's so cute.
好可愛喔
You've gotten even cuter.
變得更可愛了
Oh, take a seat.
請坐
-Kimchi.
-泡菜
Oh, next,
啊，接下來呢…
-let's jjan. -Jjan?
-來“jjan”吧 -“jjan”？
-Here. -Thank you.
-來 -謝謝
-Jjan.
-“jjan”
Uri Yuri, open wide.
“uri yuri”，張嘴
Sorry, too slow.
抱歉，好可惜喔
Open wide.
張嘴
So comfortable.
啊，好舒服
Hey, Tae-o.
泰晤，我問你喔
Yes?
什麼事？
Do you like books?
你喜歡看書嗎？
Yeah, I do.
嗯，喜歡啊
Even in university, I was always reading.
我在大學也一直在看書
I see.
這樣啊
Um…
那麼…
What about picture books?
繪本呢？
Picture books?
繪本？
Or manga.
還有漫畫之類的
I like them.
也喜歡喔
What kind?
你喜歡怎樣的類型？
-Time traveling? -Time traveling.
-穿越時空 -穿越時空？
Oh, superpowers. Those are fun.
哦，就是超能力那類的啊，很有趣呢
Yes.
是啊
Tae-o,
泰晤
which would you visit?
你想穿越到過去還是未來？
I…
我…
prefer the present.
喜歡現在當下
I love the present the most.
我最喜歡的是現在的樣子
In that case,
那麼…
if you could have any superpower,
假如你可以使用超能力
what would it be?
你想要什麼樣的特殊能力？
A superpower?
超能力？
What kinds are there?
有哪些呢？
For example,
比如說啊
stopping time.
暫停時間
That's no good.
不可以
Then I can't talk to you.
那樣會沒辦法和侑里小姐說話
There's also teleportation.
還有瞬間移動
That's nice.
那倒是不錯
If anything ever happens to you, I can get to you right away.
如果侑里小姐出了什麼事 我可以馬上趕過去
Then…
那麼…
What about hearing people's thoughts?
可以聽到別人心聲的能力呢？
If I could also hear people's thoughts…
如果我也可以聽到別人的心聲…
Oh.
啊
-I'm going home. -What?
-我要回去了 -什麼？
It's time.
時間很晚了
I really need to get home now.
我不回去不行
"Also"?
“也”？
-Could you please take this on? -Yes.
-麻煩你了 -好
-Keep me updated, Aihara. -Okay.
-相原，之後要再向我報告 -我知道了
Yes?
請進
Can I have a moment, Motomiya?
-本宮，現在有空嗎？ -有
-It's about the investors. -Right.
-我想談關於投資者的那件事 -好
A Korean venture capitalist is positively interested in investing.
有位韓國創投的投資家正在積極考慮
They'll tell us soon.
最近就會收到回覆
That's great. Thank you.
太好了，謝謝你
Read through these materials from the investor.
這是那位投資家的資料，你先看過吧
MIN HA-NA HOMETOWN: SEOUL, SOUTH KOREA
（閔荷娜 出生地：韓國首爾特別市）
Min Ha-na…
“閔荷娜”…
It seems she liked us at the Hokkaido get-together.
她好像是在北海道的交流會 對我們公司有了興趣
The Hokkaido get-together?
北海道的交流會？
Yeah.
對
Is something the matter?
怎麼了嗎？
No, I'll read through it.
沒事，我會看過的
Yes, thank you.
了解，謝謝，麻煩你了
Min Ha-na…
“閔荷娜”
She's from Seoul, South Korea.
出生於韓國首爾特別市
Could she be…
她該不會…
someone he knows?
是泰晤認識的人吧？
Tae-o.
泰晤
You've grown so much, Tae-o.
泰晤，你長大了呀
So, it was you, Nuna.
所以你果然是大姐姐啊
You look the same.
你都沒變呢
Have you been well?
過得好嗎？
Yeah.
很好
But what brings you here?
但你為什麼會在這裡？
I want to ask you something.
我有話要問你
This place is nice.
這裡好漂亮啊
What do you want to ask, Nuna?
姊，你想問我什麼？
When we met in Hokkaido, I thought you'd have long forgotten me,
當我們在北海道相遇 我以為你早就忘記
a nuna who only temporarily lived nearby.
以前住在你家附近一陣子的大姐姐了
Is that why you left so quickly?
所以你才突然不見？
Back then,
那個時候我覺得
I thought I was satisfied just knowing you were living well.
只要你過得好就好了
But yesterday,
不過昨天
I saw your company's CEO.
我看到你和社長…
Ms. Motomiya has the same power as me, right?
本宮小姐和我有相同的能力嗎？
And you two are dating.
而且你們在交往
Right?
對不對？
Tae-o, that's the one thing you shouldn't do.
泰晤，唯獨那樣不行！
Why does it have to be her?
為什麼偏偏是她？
Why? You know about her power.
這是為什麼？你明明知道能力的事
Tae-o.
泰晤
You know that lies
你騙我也沒用
don't work on me.
你明白吧？
It's okay.
放心啦
I don't mind.
我不要緊
It was around then.
我在那個時候就發現了
Nice to meet you.
請多多指教
MIN HA-NA
（閔荷娜）
That's when
我猜想你們兩人
I realized that you two might have
可能有相同的能力
the same power.
我是從那時開始懷疑的
I like Yuri.
我喜歡侑里小姐
Even if you two have the same power, my feelings won't change.
就算你們有相同的能力 這點也不會變
You…
你…
remember the ending of that picture book, right?
知道那繪本的結局吧？
You can't stay together.
你們不能在一起
You should break up before something happens.
最好在出事之前和她分手
It's my decision.
有權選擇的是我
And I'll take responsibility.
我也願意承擔後果
-But-- -Regardless
-可是… -不管在過去…
of what happened to you long ago
你經歷過什麼事
or how the picture book ends…
不管繪本的結局如何
I will never break up with her.
我都絕對不會和她分手
Thanks for worrying about me.
謝謝你為我擔心
I'll be going now.
我先走了
Have you lost your trust in him?
你無法相信他了嗎？
The thoughts in Tae-o's mind…
不管是泰晤在想什麼
Tae-o's feelings…
還是泰晤的心意…
What could they be?
該怎麼說好呢？
I can't tell.
我都猜不透
It's hard to understand everything about someone.
要想理解一個人的全部是很困難的
But,
不過呢
I don't think you have to doubt
他喜歡侑里的這份心意
his feelings of love for you.
不需要去懷疑吧
Sorry Tae-o, this is for your sake.
對不起，但這麼做是為了泰晤好
Is this about the investment?
是要談出資的事嗎？
No,
不是
I need to briefly return to Korea on a late-night flight tonight.
我得搭今天半夜的飛機回韓國一趟
But before that…
在那之前…
there is something
我有個東西
I want to give to Ms. Motomiya as soon as possible.
想盡快交給本宮社長
To Motomiya?
交給本宮嗎？
Shall I pass it along to her?
要我幫你轉交嗎？
Yes.
好
A picture book?
繪本？
For Motomiya? Why?
為什麼要給本宮這個？
This story…
這是…
is about me.
發生在我身上的事
What?
什麼？
The ending of this book…
這繪本的結局…
Hanaoka, what is it?
花岡，你怎麼來了？
Motomiya.
本宮
I knew it. Can you hear me?
你果然能聽到嗎？
Can you hear
能聽到…
my thoughts?
我的聲音？
I'm sorry for testing you.
對不起，竟用這種方式測試你
I need to talk to you.
我有話要跟你說
Ms. Min Ha-na
閔荷娜小姐…
came to see you.
剛才來公司找你
What?
什麼？
She wanted to give this to you.
她要我把這個交給你
This is…
這是…
She also has a message for you.
閔小姐還託我轉告你一些事
is about me.
發生在我身上的事
What?
什麼？
The ending of this book
這繪本的結局…
is something that actually happened between me and my partner.
實際發生在我和戀人身上
I don't want
我不希望…
those two to meet the same fate as us.
他們倆走上和我們相同的命運
"Something that actually happened…"
實際發生過的事？
"Us"?
她說的“我們”是？
HEAR US, HEAR US HEAR OUR CRIES
（聽我們說，聽我們的聲音）
"The girl hurried over
“少女拼命奔跑
to her loved one's side."
跑向心愛之人的身邊…
"However, fate would not wait for the two."
然而命運卻不願等到他們見面”
"The boy
“少年…
became a star, shining in the night sky."
變成了在夜空中閃爍的星星
"The boy, who became a star,
化為星星的少年一直在心裡
continued to yell his love for her in his heart."
大喊‘我愛你’
"That voice never reached the girl."
但他的聲音無法傳達給少女”
I couldn't believe
閔小姐說的話
what Ms. Min was saying at first.
我沒辦法馬上相信
So I looked into it.
所以我就去查了
Sorry.
抱歉，我竟自作主張
I thought some information might only be in Korean, so I asked Nishina to help.
我想說有些資料要用韓語才查得到 所以也拜託了仁科小姐
Then, we found
結果…
a school newspaper from Ms. Min's university 22 years ago.
找到了閔小姐就讀的大學 22年前的校內雜誌
At the time,
閔小姐當時
it seems Ms. Min had a boyfriend at the same university.
好像和同一所大學的學生在交往
While attending university, her boyfriend…
她的男友在就讀大學時…
U SEON-HO, DECEASED
（禹善浩，過世）
…passed away.
離開人世
The "us" that Ms. Min was talking about
閔小姐所說的“我們”
is about her
我想一定就是指她自己
and her deceased boyfriend.
和過世的戀人
I'm sure of it.
這點絕對沒錯
He knew everything.
原來他全都知道
Tae-o.
泰晤…
That's why he…
所以泰晤才會…
Want to go somewhere on our day off tomorrow?
明天休假要不要一起去哪裡玩？
Sure, how about Korea?
當然好，去韓國怎麼樣？
He was always
無論在何時
just treasuring the moments he had with me in the present.
都會好好珍惜和我在一起的每個當下
I prefer the present.
我喜歡現在當下
I love the present the most.
我最喜歡的是現在的樣子
Oh, Yuri?
哦，侑里小姐？
What is it?
怎麼了？
I was just missing you.
我突然想見你
I'm glad. Come in.
我好高興，請進
Thanks.
謝謝
Yuri, did you eat?
侑里小姐，你吃過飯了嗎？
Shall I make you something?
要我做點吃的給你嗎？
Sure. Sorry.
好啊，不好意思
Why are you apologizing?
為什麼要道歉？
I want to talk.
-我有話要跟你說 -那個…
can we do it after we eat?
等吃完飯再說吧
Sure.
好吧
I have japchae.
我做了“雜菜”
Five minutes.
五分鐘就好
It'll be done soon.
馬上就可以吃了
Take a seat.
請坐
Tae-o.
泰晤
Listen.
聽我說
I…
我…
Meeting you…
自從遇見你
Falling in love with you…
喜歡上你之後
That's the first time
才第一次明白
I realized what loving someone is like.
喜歡一個人是怎樣的感覺
I felt happy.
會很高興
I felt pained.
會感到揪心
I felt scared.
會很害怕
I felt blessed.
卻無比幸福
I was surprised I could feel such a whirlwind of emotions.
我察覺到自己的內心 原來有這麼多種瞬息萬變的情感
I only know this
因為有泰晤
because I met you.
才讓我明白了這點喔
Thank you so much.
真的很謝謝你
Tae-o…
泰晤…
I love you.
我非常喜歡你
So, let's break up.
所以我們分手吧
Why?
為什麼？
Did you find out?
你發現了嗎？
It doesn't matter.
那都不成問題
Yuri,
我真的…
I truly love you.
非常喜歡侑里小姐喔
Yuri.
侑里小姐
Thank you.
謝謝你
MICROPHONE
（語音）
DON'T GO
（不要走）
"The boy became a star, shining in the night sky."
少年變成了在夜空中閃爍的星星
Yuri!
侑里小姐！
"The boy, who became a star, continued to yell
化為星星的少年一直在心裡
his love for her in his heart."
大喊“我愛你”
"That voice never reached the girl."
但他的聲音無法傳達給少女
Why did you make such a sad story?
為什麼要寫這麼悲傷的故事呢？
The person I loved
大姐姐的戀人啊
became a star, just like this boy.
跟這少年一樣，變成星星了
Because I loved him.
都怪我愛上他
You know, Tae-o,
你要記好喔，泰晤
in this world,
在這個世界上…
there are people who you must never love.
有絕對不能去愛的人
Subtitle translation by: Chul Woong Kim
字幕翻譯：劉翠恬